Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم الإدارة، شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
[Chunyun House]
[بيت تشونيون]
Your Excellency.
صاحب السعادة.
You haven't slept all night.
لم تنم طوال الليل.
Take a break.
خذ استراحة.
Still no news from Mr. Feng?
ما زال السيد فينغ لم يأتِ على أي أخبار؟
Your Excellency, don't worry.
صاحب السعادة، لا تقلق.
Mr. Feng is very resourceful.
السيد فينغ يتمتع بحس عالٍ من الحيلة.
He'll be fine.
سيكون بخير.
I always feel a bit panicky.
أشعر دائمًا ببعض الذعر.
Pass on my order.
مرر طلبي.
Everyone in the Hearsay-capturing Pavilion
جميع من في جناح التقاط الشائعات
should stand down.
ينبغي عليه أن يتنحى.
Yes,
نعم،
Your Excellency.
صاحب السعادة.
[Treasure at Dawn] ♪Reach the highest level♪
[كنز عند الفجر] ♪الوصول إلى أعلى مستوى♪
♪Reach the state of no desire, illuminate the virtuous light♪
♪بلغ حالة انعدام الرغبة، وأضئ النور الفاضل♪
♪Man is upright because he is moral, and he is strong because he is upright♪
الإنسان مستقيم لأنه أخلاقي، وهو قوي لأنه مستقيم.
♪Upright, strong, and fair♪
♪مستقيم، قوي، وعادل♪
♪I am the fire♪
♪أنا النار♪
♪Burning out all desires♪
♪إخماد كل الرغبات♪
♪River can't put me out♪
♪ لن يستطيع النهر إخمادي ♪
♪Yang's beginning leads to development. Wu Chi creates Tai Chi♪
♪بداية اليانغ تؤدي إلى التطور. وو تشي تُنشئ التاي تشي♪
♪People are blinded by body and form, letting delusion rule their hearts♪
♪ينبهر الناس بالجسد والشكل، ويتركون الوهم يسيطر على قلوبهم♪
♪People make their own enemies♪
♪الناس يصنعون أعداءهم بأنفسهم♪
♪Books are all about reason. People are full of purpose♪
♪الكتب كلها تدور حول العقل. أما البشر فمفعمون بالهدف♪
♪People are overrun by illusions♪
♪الناس غارقون في الأوهام♪
♪They are fascinated by illusions♪
♪إنهم مفتونون بالأوهام♪
♪With a pure mind, sitting in the clouds♪
♪بذهن صافٍ، جالسًا بين الغيوم♪
♪Watching people creating dreams♪
♪مشاهدة الناس وهم يصنعون أحلامهم♪
♪Is it painful to live in the world?♪
هل العيش في هذا العالم مؤلم؟
♪Learn from nature. Forget all your desires♪
♪تعلم من الطبيعة. انسَ كل رغباتك♪
♪How about clearing all my thoughts?♪
♪ماذا عن تصفية كل أفكاري؟♪
♪Moths fly into the fire♪
♪العث يطير إلى النار♪
♪The fire melts old shackles♪
♪النار تذيب القيود القديمة♪
♪Today, I know it's me♪
اليوم، أعرف أنني أنا من يجب أن يكون كذلك.
[Treasure at Dawn]
[كنز عند الفجر]
[Episode 25] [Twin Heroes in a Trap, the Painting Reappears]
[الحلقة 25] [بطلان توأمان في فخ، اللوحة تظهر من جديد]
It's dawn.
لقد بزغ الفجر.
Oh, no. How did I fall asleep?
يا إلهي! كيف نمت؟
I didn't go back all night,
لم أعد طوال الليل،
so my father must be worried about me.
إذن لا بد أن والدي قلق عليّ.
Why hasn't Feng Qianli returned?
لماذا لم يعد فنغ تشيانلي؟
Meng Qin is missing too.
منغ تشين مفقودة أيضاً.
Meng Qin probably went out
من المحتمل أن مينغ تشين قد خرجت
snooping for information because
التجسس للحصول على المعلومات لأن
he was worried about his wife and son.
كان قلقاً على زوجته وابنه.
That worries me.
هذا الأمر يقلقني.
I have to go to the Jibei Chamber of Commerce to see him.
عليّ الذهاب إلى غرفة تجارة جيبي لرؤيته.
No.
لا.
It's too dangerous.
الأمر خطير للغاية.
At this point, don't stop me.
في هذه المرحلة، لا توقفني.
I have to go.
يجب على  أن أذهب.
It's daytime,
إنه وقت النهار،
so how will you get there?
فكيف ستصل إلى هناك؟
The same way as before.
بنفس الطريقة السابقة.
As before.
كما كان من قبل.
What will you say then?
ماذا ستقول حينها؟
Are you going to ask Sun Siming,
هل ستسأل صن سينغ؟
"Did you see Feng Qianli last night?"
"هل رأيت فنغ تشيانلي الليلة الماضية؟"
or
أو
"Did you catch Meng Qin this morning?"
"هل قابلت منغ تشين هذا الصباح؟"
I won't say that,
لن أقول ذلك،
so I need you to help me.
لذا أحتاج مساعدتك.
Me?
أنا؟
You want me in the dark while you're in the open?
أتريدني أن أكون في الظلام بينما أنت في العراء؟
Yeah.
نعم.
Then I'll go too.
سأذهب أنا أيضاً.
I'll keep them in check.
سأراقبهم وأسيطر عليهم.
- Let's go.- OK.
- هيا بنا. - حسناً.
Jiu.
جيو.
Did you sleep here last night?
هل نمت هنا الليلة الماضية؟
Do you realize what you did was wrong?
هل تدرك أن ما فعلته كان خطأ؟
Jiu.
جيو.
Yes.
نعم.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
His Excellency is waiting for you at the mansion.
معالي السيد ينتظركم في القصر.
I can't go.
لا أستطيع الذهاب.
By the way, Jiu.
بالمناسبة، جيو.
You're good at fighting,
أنت بارع في القتال،
so can you do me a small favor?
هل يمكنك أن تسدي لي معروفاً صغيراً؟
[Linrong Umbrella Repairing]
[إصلاح مظلات لينرونغ]
Are you feeling cold?
هل تشعر بالبرد؟
No, I'm not.
لا، لست كذلك.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Don't ask. Come on.
لا تسأل. هيا.
- Come on. - Where are you taking us?
- هيا بنا. - إلى أين تأخذنا؟
[Jibei Chamber of Commerce]
[غرفة تجارة جيبي]
Who are you?
من أنت؟
Please inform Chairman Sun
يرجى إبلاغ رئيس مجلس الإدارة صن
that Fu Sheng wants to see him.
أن فو شنغ يريد رؤيته.
Do you think you can meet him at will?
هل تعتقدين أنه يمكنكِ مقابلته متى شئتِ؟
Go away.
يبتعد.
Why are you pushing him?
لماذا تضغط عليه؟
Do you know who I am?
هل تعرف من أنا؟
Who are you?
من أنت؟
Young Mistress of Xichuan.
سيدة شيتشوان الشابة.
Young Mistress, please forgive me
سيدتي الشابة، أرجو أن تسامحيني
for being blind.
لكونه أعمى.
Then call out
ثم نادِ
your Chairman Sun now.
رئيس مجلس إدارتكم، صن، الآن.
Our Chairman is not here.
رئيس مجلس إدارتنا ليس هنا.
He just went out.
لقد خرج للتو.
The Chairman isn't here?
أليس الرئيس هنا؟
The Vice Chairman?
نائب الرئيس؟
Yes.
نعم.
Lead us to her.
أرشدنا إليها.
Please.
لو سمحت.
[Jibei Chamber of Commerce]
[غرفة تجارة جيبي]
The dungeon is over there.
الزنزانة هناك.
Mother, where are we going?
يا أمي، إلى أين نحن ذاهبون؟
Mother, are we going to die?
يا أمي، هل سنموت؟
No, we're not.
لا، لسنا كذلك.
I will protect you with my life.
سأحميك بروحي.
What's going on here?
ما الذي يحدث هنا؟
What crime
أي جريمة؟
has a child this young committed?
هل سبق أن تم إيداع طفل صغير في مثل هذا السن في دار رعاية؟
I want to know too.
أريد أن أعرف أيضاً.
It's too bad.
هذا مؤسف للغاية.
Yes.
نعم.
They're pathetic.
إنهم مثيرون للشفقة.
You've been sitting here for a quarter of an hour
لقد جلست هنا لمدة ربع ساعة
and haven't said why you're here,
ولم توضح سبب وجودك هنا،
but that's all right.
لكن لا بأس.
I'm not busy anyway.
أنا لست مشغولاً على أي حال.
When will Chairman Sun be back?
متى سيعود الرئيس صن؟
Chairman Sun is busy outside,
الرئيس صن مشغول في الخارج،
so I'm afraid he won't be back for a while.
لذا أخشى أنه لن يعود لفترة من الوقت.
Physician Fu, you can
الطبيب فو، يمكنك
tell me anything.
أخبرني بأي شيء.
Then we'll wait a little longer.
ثم سننتظر قليلاً.
No problem.
لا مشكلة.
Then let's stay for lunch.
فلنبقَ لتناول الغداء.
Chairman Guo, what do you mean?
الرئيس غو، ماذا تقصد؟
What can I mean?
ماذا أقصد؟
I want to keep my guests,
أريد أن أحافظ على ضيوفي،
so I have to be sincere.
لذا عليّ أن أكون صادقاً.
Young Mistress, you live a good life,
سيدتي الشابة، أنتِ تعيشين حياة طيبة.
so you won't be used
لذلك لن يتم استغلالك
to our humble food.
إلى طعامنا المتواضع.
You can help yourself,
يمكنك مساعدة نفسك،
but Physician Fu must stay.
لكن يجب أن يبقى الطبيب فو.
Fu Sheng is my man.
فو شنغ هو رجلي.
Since I brought him here, I'll take him away.
بما أنني أحضرته إلى هنا، فسآخذه بعيداً.
If he doesn't leave, neither will I.
إذا لم يرحل هو، فلن أرحل أنا أيضاً.
But I must kindly remind you.
لكن يجب أن أذكرك بلطف.
In Xichuan, everyone knows
في شيتشوان، الجميع يعرف
that my father cares about me the most.
أن والدي يهتم بي أكثر من أي شخص آخر.
If he knows I am under house arrest
إذا كان يعلم أنني رهن الإقامة الجبرية
by the Jibei Chamber of Commerce,
من قبل غرفة تجارة جيبي،
guess what will happen.
خمن ماذا سيحدث.
Fu Sheng, let's go.
فو شنغ، هيا بنا.
Madam, why are we afraid of Lord's Mansion?
سيدتي، لماذا نخاف من قصر اللورد؟
Wouldn't it be better to detain them
أليس من الأفضل احتجازهم؟
to force them to hand over the jade plate?
لإجبارهم على تسليم طبق اليشم؟
We haven't got the map yet,
لم نحصل على الخريطة بعد،
so we can't turn our backs on them now
لذا لا يمكننا أن ندير ظهورنا لهم الآن
in case something unexpected happens.
في حال حدوث شيء غير متوقع.
Let's just hold out.
فلنصبر قليلاً.
This is your home.
هذا هو منزلك.
Madam, don't be afraid.
سيدتي، لا تخافي.
I won't eat you.
لن آكلك.
I just want to ask you.
أريد فقط أن أسألك.
Do you know
هل تعلم
where Meng Qin hid that?
أين أخفى منغ تشين ذلك؟
Hid what?
أخفى ماذا؟
I don't know.
لا أعرف.
Makes sense. He wouldn't tell you
هذا منطقي. لن يخبرك بذلك.
something so important to keep it a secret.
شيء بالغ الأهمية بحيث يجب إبقاؤه سراً.
Okay.
تمام.
Then let me ask you.
إذن دعني أسألك.
Do you know where Meng Qin is?
هل تعرف أين مينغ تشين؟
Don't blame me
لا تلومني
if you don't know anything.
إذا كنت لا تعرف أي شيء.
Guys.
شباب.
Yes.
نعم.
You have to find it even if
عليك أن تجده حتى لو
you have to dig through the ground.
عليك أن تحفر في الأرض.
- Yes, sir. Get in. - Yes, sir.
- نعم سيدي. تفضل بالدخول. - نعم سيدي.
What's going on?
ماذا يحدث هنا؟
They're not in the dungeon.
إنهم ليسوا في الزنزانة.
All we know is that
كل ما نعرفه هو أن
someone did break into the Chamber of Commerce yesterday.
لقد اقتحم أحدهم غرفة التجارة أمس.
Looks like Feng Qianli's in a bad way.
يبدو الأمر مشابهاً لفنغ تشيانلي، ولكن بطريقة سيئة.
There's one more piece of news.
هناك خبر آخر.
Meng Qin's family was taken away
تم اقتياد عائلة منغ تشين
by Sun Siming this morning.
بقلم صن سيمينغ هذا الصباح.
Taken away?
أُخذت بعيداً؟
Let's save them.
لننقذهم.
Do you know where they are?
هل تعرف أين هم؟
Why in such a hurry?
لماذا هذه العجلة؟
They must be in the Meng's.
لا بد أنهم من عائلة مينغ.
Young Mistress.
سيدتي الشابة.
I've done the favor
لقد قدمتُ المعروف
you asked me to do,
طلبتَ مني أن أفعل،
so you have to come back with me.
لذا عليك العودة معي.
Jiu.
جيو.
Chairman, nothing.
الرئيس، لا شيء.
As the old saying goes, one can't bring a disaster to the family.
كما يقول المثل القديم، لا يمكن للمرء أن يجلب كارثة للعائلة.
He should take responsibility.
عليه أن يتحمل المسؤولية.
This has nothing
هذا لا شيء
to do with you,
فيما يتعلق بك،
but I despise people
لكنني أكره الناس
who don't care about their families
الذين لا يهتمون بعائلاتهم
when things go wrong.
عندما تسوء الأمور.
Madam, I'm so sad for you.
سيدتي، أشعر بحزن شديد لأجلك.
Meng Qin.
منغ تشين.
Since you're shameless,
بما أنك عديم الحياء،
I'll do as you wish.
سأفعل ما تشاء.
Strip her naked
انزعي عنها ملابسها
and leave her at the door
واتركها عند الباب
for all his neighbors to see.
ليراه جميع جيرانه.
The backbone of the Meng family,
العمود الفقري لعائلة مينغ،
the hero.
البطل.
Put her clothes on
ألبسها ملابسها
when Meng Qin appears.
عندما يظهر منغ تشين.
Let go of me.
اتركني وشأني.
Don't bully my mother.
لا تتنمر على أمي.
Help me. Let go of him.
ساعدني. اتركه.
Hang her up.
أغلق الخط عليها.
See?
يرى؟
Wouldn't it have been fine if you'd shown up earlier?
ألم يكن الأمر سيكون على ما يرام لو حضرت في وقت أبكر؟
Why do you make me do things I don't want to do?
لماذا تجبرني على فعل أشياء لا أريد فعلها؟
Honey.
عسل.
Just give them whatever they want.
أعطهم ما يريدون.
I haven't begged you in all these years.
لم أتوسل إليك طوال هذه السنوات.
Just give it to him.
أعطه إياه.
Madam is right.
السيدة على حق.
Why is he in such a hurry?
لماذا هو في عجلة من أمره؟
Exactly.
بالضبط.
Hello, My Lord.
مرحباً يا سيدي.
My Lord.
يا سيدي.
Did you call us here
هل اتصلت بنا هنا؟
to discuss something important?
لمناقشة أمر هام؟
I'm traveling
أنا مسافر
to Xichuan in a few days.
إلى شيتشوان خلال أيام قليلة.
When I leave Jibei,
عندما أغادر جيبي،
I'll have peace of mind
سأشعر براحة البال
if you can handle the affairs
إذا كنت تستطيع إدارة الأمور
of the royal household.
من العائلة المالكة.
My Lord, don't worry.
يا سيدي، لا تقلق.
We will do our best.
سنبذل قصارى جهدنا.
Liu Luan may not be on our side anymore,
ربما لم يعد ليو لوان في صفنا بعد الآن،
but I have taken control of him with Japonicus.
لكنني سيطرت عليه بمساعدة جابونيكوس.
When I go to Xichuan,
عندما أذهب إلى شيتشوان،
I will take him with me
سآخذه معي
to prevent him from interfering in the government.
لمنعه من التدخل في شؤون الحكومة.
After I leave, Sage Can,
بعد رحيلي، سيج كان،
please take care of the treasury and taxes.
يرجى الاهتمام بالخزينة والضرائب.
Yes, sir.
نعم سيدي.
Sage Mao.
ماو الحكيم.
You recommended Du Shang,
لقد أوصيت بـ دو شانغ،
and he helped me a lot.
وقد ساعدني كثيراً.
I'll leave the military affairs
سأترك الشؤون العسكرية
to you and Sage Kui.
إلى كل منكما وإلى الحكيم كوي.
Yes, sir.
نعم سيدي.
I'll drink tea
سأشرب الشاي
to the three of you.
لكم أنتم الثلاثة.
It's our job.
هذا عملنا.
You're welcome, My Lord.
أهلاً بك يا سيدي.
We await your triumph.
ننتظر انتصارك.
I've hidden the Painting of Luan
لقد أخفيت لوحة لوان
in a hut in the mountains outside the city.
في كوخ في الجبال خارج المدينة.
Enter the mountains from the north entrance,
ادخل الجبال من المدخل الشمالي،
cross three hills,
عبور ثلاث تلال،
go west for a mile,
اتجه غرباً لمسافة ميل واحد،
and go north when you
واتجه شمالاً عندما...
meet the fork in the road.
واجه مفترق الطرق.
Then you will see the hut.
ثم سترى الكوخ.
Just in case you're lying to me,
تحسباً لأنك تكذب عليّ،
please
لو سمحت
take us there.
خذنا إلى هناك.
It seems we are late after all.
يبدو أننا تأخرنا في النهاية.
Fu Sheng.
فو شنغ.
Look at this.
انظر إلى هذا.
[Xichuan]
[شيتشوان]
It's a different color inside.
لونه مختلف من الداخل.
It should have just been carved.
كان ينبغي أن يتم نحته فقط.
I think this should be the clue
أعتقد أن هذا يجب أن يكون الدليل
Meng Qin left us.
لقد رحل منغ تشين عنا.
What kind of clue is it?
ما نوع هذا الدليل؟
It's a map.
إنها خريطة.
I didn't realize you
لم أكن أدركك
had such a large courtyard here,
كان لدينا فناء كبير هنا،
but I don't know
لكنني لا أعرف
if there's an ambush here.
إذا كان هناك كمين هنا.
Cut the crap. Let go of me.
كفى هراءً. دعني وشأني.
I'll take you in.
سأدخلك.
It's inside.
إنه بالداخل.
Are there
هل يوجد
any traps in here?
هل يوجد أي فخاخ هنا؟
No.
لا.
If you
إذا كنت
hadn't been willing to bring me here,
لم يكونوا مستعدين لإحضاري إلى هنا،
I might have been more at ease,
ربما كنت سأكون أكثر ارتياحاً،
but you've been walking so smoothly
لكنك كنت تمشي بسلاسة شديدة
and in such a hurry all this way,
وبكل هذه العجلة طوال هذه المسافة،
so your mind is so obvious that even a fool can see it.
لذا فإن عقلك واضح لدرجة أن حتى الأحمق يستطيع أن يراه.
Are you afraid?
هل أنت خائف؟
How about this?
ما رأيك بهذا؟
You, go in and get
ادخل واحصل على
the Painting of Luan with him.
لوحة لوان معه.
I will wait for you
أنا سوف أنتظرك
outside with your wife and children.
اخرج مع زوجتك وأطفالك.
When you give me the Painting of Luan,
عندما تعطيني لوحة لوان،
I'll return your wife and child to you.
سأعيد إليك زوجتك وطفلك.
Go.
يذهب.
Now that you're married to him,
الآن وقد تزوجتِ منه،
accept what happens.
تقبّل ما يحدث.
It's your destiny.
إنه قدرك.
Surely, there is a trap.
بالتأكيد، هناك فخ.
Meng Qin.
منغ تشين.
Don't you care about the lives of your wife and child?
ألا تهتم بحياة زوجتك وطفلك؟
I will kill them.
سأقتلهم.
Kill them.
اقتلهم.
Please spare my life.
أرجوكم ارحموني.
Got the painting?
هل حصلت على اللوحة؟
Chairman Guo.
الرئيس غو.
This guy is so cunning.
هذا الرجل ماكر للغاية.
I almost had it.
كنت على وشك تحقيق ذلك.
Which means you didn't get it?
وهذا يعني أنك لم تفهم الأمر؟
Thank you for saving my life.
شكراً لك على إنقاذ حياتي.
I don't have it now,
ليس لديّ الآن،
but I have a countermeasure.
لكن لديّ إجراء مضاد.
Meng Qin.
منغ تشين.
He's still breathing.
لا يزال يتنفس.
Help him up.
ساعده على النهوض.
Meng Qin.
منغ تشين.
Is that Sun Siming?
هل هذا برنامج Sun Siming؟
Save my wife and son.
أنقذوا زوجتي وابني.
It's too late.
لقد فات الأوان.
Tell me.
أخبرني.
Where's the map you said you'd use
أين الخريطة التي قلت إنك ستستخدمها؟
to decipher the mechanism?
لفك شفرة الآلية؟
I am sorry.
أنا آسف.
I lied to you
لقد كذبت عليك
to save my wife and son.
لإنقاذ زوجتي وابني.
There's...
هناك...
There's no map.
لا توجد خريطة.
What did I say?
ماذا قلت؟
It's all a lie, but you don't believe me.
كل هذا كذب، لكنك لا تصدقني.
Painting...
تلوين...
Painting of Luan.
لوحة لوان.
The bucket at the bottom of the well.
الدلو الموجود في قاع البئر.
I didn't...
لم أكن...
I didn't tell them where it really is.
لم أخبرهم بمكانه الحقيقي.
You. Run.
أنت. اركض.
He'll kill you
سيقتلك
after he
بعد أن
gets the painting.
يحصل على اللوحة.
Put him down.
أنزله أرضاً.
Is this the Painting of Luan?
هل هذه لوحة لوان؟
[Painting of Luan's hiding place] No, it's not.
[لوحة لمخبأ لوان] لا، ليس كذلك.
This is the real hiding place of the Painting of Luan.
هذا هو المكان الحقيقي لإخفاء لوحة لوان.
It seems a dying man
يبدو أنه رجل يحتضر
speaks the truth.
يقول الحقيقة.
This time, he's not fooling us.
هذه المرة، لن يخدعنا.
He just said we should run
قال فقط إنه يجب علينا أن نهرب
because he was afraid Sun Siming would kill me
لأنه كان يخشى أن يقتلني سون سيمينغ
for the Bird Jade Plate.
لطبق اليشم على شكل طائر.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
You'd better not go.
من الأفضل ألا تذهب.
I think Sun Siming
أعتقد أن شركة صن سينغ
is ambushing us nearby.
إنهم ينصبون لنا كميناً في مكان قريب.
Then I have to go.
ثم عليّ أن أذهب.
Nerds like you can't fight.
أمثالك من المهووسين لا يستطيعون القتال.
With your Ghost Needle,
باستخدام إبرة الشبح الخاصة بك،
you might turn into a ghost.
قد تتحول إلى شبح.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
I've had nothing but luck
لم يحالفني الحظ إلا كلياً
in my life.
في حياتي.
Take the time
خصص بعض الوقت
to read what it says.
أن تقرأ ما يقوله.
The sun travels west, and the pavilion appears.
تتحرك الشمس غرباً، ويظهر الجناح.
The grass is sparse on the hillside.
العشب قليل على سفح التل.
What does that mean?
ماذا يعني ذلك؟
The sun travels west.
تتجه الشمس غرباً.
It's just right now.
الأمر مناسب تماماً الآن.
The pavilion.
الجناح.
There.
هناك.
What else does it say?
ماذا يقول أيضاً؟
Green bamboo leaves, the Xuan shines.
أوراق الخيزران الخضراء، يتألق نهر شوان.
The red in the green indicates its location.
يشير اللون الأحمر داخل اللون الأخضر إلى موقعه.
"Green bamboo leaves" refers to this bamboo forest.
يشير مصطلح "أوراق الخيزران الخضراء" إلى غابة الخيزران هذه.
Xuan
شوان
means Luan.
يعني لوان.
So the Painting of Luan is here.
إذن، لوحة لوان موجودة هنا.
How are we supposed to find it in such a big bamboo forest?
كيف يُفترض بنا أن نجده في غابة خيزران بهذا الحجم؟
It also says "red in the green".
ويقول أيضًا "الأحمر في الأخضر".
Where's the red color
أين اللون الأحمر؟
in all this green?
وسط كل هذه المساحات الخضراء؟
Let's split up and look for it.
لننفصل ونبحث عنه.
I'll go there.
سأذهب إلى هناك.
You go there.
اذهب إلى هناك.
Red in the green.
الأحمر في الأخضر.
Gu Tian, I found it.
غو تيان، لقد وجدته.
"Red in the green"
"الأحمر في الأخضر"
must be this spot.
لا بد أن يكون هذا هو المكان.
I'll dig.
سأفعل لك.
I don't want
أنا لا أريد
to burden you with this physical labor.
أن أثقل كاهلك بهذا العمل البدني.
Painting of Luan? Shouldn't this be Ball of Luan?
لوحة لخشب لوان؟ ألا يجب أن تكون هذه كرة من خشب لوان؟
You're a disaster for me.
أنت كارثة بالنسبة لي.
I always said my life
لطالما قلت حياتي
would be lost because of you.
سيضيعون بسببك.
Looks like it's going to come true this time.
يبدو أن الأمر سيتحقق هذه المرة.
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
Fu Sheng.
فو شنغ.
The Bird Jade Plate has always been
لطالما كان طبق اليشم الطائر
with you,
معك،
but you never mentioned it.
لكنك لم تذكر ذلك أبداً.
You didn't think of me as a friend.
لم تعتبرني صديقاً.
The people who were your friends are dead.
الأشخاص الذين كانوا أصدقاءك قد ماتوا.
I don't agree with you on that.
لا أتفق معك في ذلك.
I've always treated you
لقد عاملتك دائماً
like brothers.
مثل الإخوة.
Have I ever refused to help you
هل سبق لي أن رفضت مساعدتك؟
when you came to me?
متى أتيت إلي؟
But when it comes to the Treasure of the Sealed Book,
لكن عندما يتعلق الأمر بكنز الكتاب المختوم،
you just care about making money
كل ما يهمك هو كسب المال
and never mentioned it to me.
ولم يذكر ذلك لي أبداً.
I'm disappointed.
أشعر بخيبة أمل.
Cut the crap.
كفى هراءً.
Get down to business.
فلنبدأ العمل.
See?
يرى؟
Chairman Guo is very impatient.
الرئيس غو متسرع للغاية.
OK.
نعم.
I won't talk any more.
لن أتحدث بعد الآن.
Let's get down to business.
لنبدأ العمل.
Hand over the Bird Jade Plate
سلّم طبق اليشم على شكل طائر
and the three pieces of jade.
والقطع الثلاث من اليشم.
I know
أنا أعرف
you've already got your hands on them.
لقد حصلت عليها بالفعل.
Come on.
تعال.
I don't have them.
ليس لديّ هذه الأشياء.
You don't have them?
أليس لديكم؟
Search him.
ابحث عنه.
Where did you put it?
أين وضعته؟
Somewhere safe
مكان آمن
where you won't find it.
حيث لن تجده.
I told you I'd get you out safe and sound.
قلت لك سأخرجك سالماً معافى.
Still want me to keep the jade plate for you?
هل ما زلت تريدني أن أحتفظ بصحن اليشم من أجلك؟
Take it.
خذها.
It's more secure.
إنه أكثر أمانًا.
That makes sense.
هذا منطقي.
Kill them.
اقتلهم.
Kill them?
هل نقتلهم؟
These two know too much,
هذان الشخصان يعرفان الكثير،
so we need to prevent future problems.
لذا علينا منع حدوث مشاكل مستقبلية.
But we haven't found the Bird Jade Plate.
لكننا لم نعثر على طبق اليشم الخاص بالطائر.
It must be in that clinic
لا بد أن يكون في تلك العيادة
or
أو
with that little girl from the Lord's Mansion.
مع تلك الفتاة الصغيرة من قصر الرب.
I got you, didn't I?
لقد أمسكت بك، أليس كذلك؟
Do it.
افعلها.
Actually,
في الحقيقة،
Chairman Guo,
الرئيس غو،
I owe
وهؤلاء
Fu Sheng a favor,
فو شنغ صالح ،
so could you spare their lives
هل يمكنك إذن إنقاذ حياتهم؟
for my sake?
من أجلي؟
For your sake?
من أجلك؟
Who do you think you are?
من تظن نفسك؟
If you can't find the Bird Jade Plate,
إذا لم تتمكن من العثور على طبق اليشم على شكل طائر،
you won't live either.
لن تعيش أنت أيضاً.
My friends.
أصدقائي.
You saw it.
لقد رأيت ذلك.
That's all I can do for you,
هذا كل ما أستطيع فعله من أجلك،
but I promise
لكنني أعدك
I'll visit your tombs on this day next year.
سأزور قبوركم في مثل هذا اليوم من العام المقبل.
And I'll bring with me one,
وسأحضر معي واحدة،
sorry, two jars of good wine.
عفواً، مرطبانان من النبيذ الجيد.
Rest in peace,
ارقد في سلام،
friends.
أصدقاء.
Wait a minute.
انتظر دقيقة.
I have something to say.
لديّ ما أقوله.
Fu Sheng, before we die,
فو شنغ، قبل أن نموت،
can you fulfill a wish of mine?
هل يمكنك تحقيق أمنية لي؟
What wish?
أي أمنية؟
Call me brother.
نادني أخي.
Do you know what's the occasion now?
هل تعلم ما هي المناسبة الآن؟
Can you? Answer me.
هل يمكنك ذلك؟ أجبني.
I...
أنا...
Brother.
أخ.
What? I didn't hear you.
ماذا؟ لم أسمعك.
So nosy even at the end of your lives.
فضوليون للغاية حتى في نهاية حياتكم.
We didn't expect you
لم نكن نتوقعك
to be disturbed by our internal affairs.
أن ننزعج من شؤوننا الداخلية.
Chairman Sun, you thought too much.
رئيس مجلس الإدارة صن، لقد فكرت كثيراً.
We didn't want to interfere with you guys at first,
لم نكن نرغب في التدخل في شؤونكم في البداية،
but as the saying goes,
لكن كما يقول المثل،
little help brings much return.
مساعدة قليلة تجلب عائداً كبيراً.
Fu Sheng is my savior.
فو شنغ هو منقذي.
If something were to happen to him in Xichuan,
إذا حدث له مكروه في شيتشوان،
I, as city lord,
أنا، بصفتي سيد المدينة،
would be mortified.
سيشعر بالخجل الشديد.
You're worrying too much.
أنت تقلق كثيراً.
Fu Sheng is my good friend
فو شنغ صديقي العزيز
and saved my life.
وأنقذ حياتي.
We're joking.
نحن نمزح.
That's good.
هذا جيد.
In that case,
في هذه الحالة،
can I take him away?
هل يمكنني أخذه بعيداً؟
Of course.
بالطبع.
Are you hurt?
هل أنت مصاب؟
No. You're just in time.
لا، لقد وصلت في الوقت المناسب تماماً.
Luckily, you told Wen Jue before you came.
لحسن الحظ، أخبرتَ وين جو قبل مجيئك.
Let's go. She's waiting for us at the bottom of the hill.
هيا بنا. إنها تنتظرنا أسفل التل.
What will you do about the jade plate?
ماذا ستفعل بشأن الصفيحة المصنوعة من اليشم؟
Chairman Guo, don't worry.
لا تقلق يا رئيس مجلس الإدارة غو.
I have a plan,
لدي خطة،
but before we get the jade plate,
لكن قبل أن نحصل على الصفيحة اليشمية،
there's one more thing we need to take care of.
هناك أمر آخر نحتاج إلى الاهتمام به.
This
هذا
is a list of three thousand spies,
هي قائمة تضم ثلاثة آلاف جاسوس،
copied by my men from Feng Qianli.
قام رجالي بنسخها من فنغ تشيانلي.
This man has been in Xichuan for years
هذا الرجل موجود في شيتشوان منذ سنوات
and has much access to information.
ويتمتع بإمكانية الوصول إلى الكثير من المعلومات.
Now that he's heard the Lord's name,
والآن بعد أن سمع اسم الرب،
I'm worried that, before he died,
أنا قلق من أنه قبل وفاته،
he already passed on the news
لقد نقل الخبر بالفعل
in ways we don't know about.
بطرق لا نعرفها.
Whether he knows it or not,
سواء كان يعلم ذلك أم لا،
Lord's plan
خطة الرب
can't be compromised.
لا يمكن التنازل عنها.
Eliminate
اِسْتَبْعَد
the Hearsay-capturing Pavilion.
جناح التقاط الشائعات.
Yes, Madam.
نعم سيدتي.
You, come here.
تعال إلى هنا.
Take some men to the Hearsay-capturing Pavilion
اصطحب بعض الرجال إلى جناح التقاط الشائعات
and kill those on this list,
واقتل أولئك الموجودين في هذه القائمة،
no, everyone.
لا، الجميع.
All of them.
جميعهم.
Understood.
مفهوم.
Sun Siming, you've killed so many people,
سون سيمينغ، لقد قتلت الكثير من الناس،
so how will you explain this to the Lord's Mansion?
فكيف ستشرح هذا الأمر لدار الرب؟
I've already arranged a scapegoat.
لقد رتبت بالفعل كبش فداء.
You're despicable.
أنت حقير.
Now that you're safely in town
الآن وقد وصلت إلى المدينة بأمان
and I have work, I'll see you later.
ولدي عمل، أراك لاحقاً.
Lord Wen, thank you for your help.
يا سيد وين، شكراً لك على مساعدتك.
The Chamber of Commerce is intent on killing you,
غرفة التجارة عازمة على قتلك،
so be careful in the future.
لذا كن حذراً في المستقبل.
I understand.
أفهم.
Thanks for the reminder, Lord Wen.
شكراً على التذكير، يا لورد وين.
Jue, come back with me.
جو، عد معي.
Father.
أب.
You've worked hard all the way.
لقد بذلت جهداً كبيراً طوال الطريق.
Go back and rest.
ارجع واسترح.
See you later.
أراك لاحقًا.
I'll see you tomorrow.
أراك غداً.
Let's go back to the clinic now.
لنعد إلى العيادة الآن.
[Chunyun House] Come back tomorrow.
[بيت تشون يون] عد غداً.
Sir, come back tomorrow.
سيدي، عد غداً.
See you later.
أراك لاحقًا.
Watch the threshold.
انتبه للعتبة.
- Careful. - Watch out.
- انتبه. - احذر.
Lian, close the door.
ليان، أغلقي الباب.
Okay, go to bed.
حسناً، اذهب إلى النوم.
I'll close the door.
سأغلق الباب.
I'm coming. Did you drop something?
أنا قادم. هل أسقطت شيئاً؟
Mr. Feng? What are you doing here?
سيد فينغ؟ ماذا تفعل هنا؟
Run.
يجري.
[Xiangluo Casino]
[كازينو شيانغلو]
Your Excellency.
صاحب السعادة.
The Hearsay-capturing Pavilion's secrets have leaked.
تم تسريب أسرار جناح التقاط الشائعات.
Jibei Chamber of Commerce's men are coming to kill us.
رجال غرفة تجارة جيبي قادمون لقتلنا.
Run.
يجري.
Where's Feng Qianli?
أين فنغ تشيانلي؟
Did something happen to him?
هل حدث له مكروه؟
Your Excellency, just go.
صاحب السعادة، تفضل بالذهاب.
You're all staying here,
ستبقون جميعاً هنا،
so where can I go?
إذن إلى أين يمكنني الذهاب؟
I can't
لا أستطبع
leave you guys here
أترككم هنا
to be the only one left.
أن أكون الشخص الوحيد المتبقي.
Ms. Jiu.
السيدة جيو.
Yingying.
يينغ يينغ.
Gu Tian.
قو تيان.
[Cleaning Room]
[غرفة التنظيف]
What's going on?
ماذا يحدث هنا؟
Physician Fu.
الطبيب فو.
Hearsay-capturing Pavilion was destroyed.
تم تدمير الجناح الذي كان يُستخدم لجمع المعلومات غير الموثقة.
Gu Tian was wounded trying to save me.
أصيب غو تيان بجروح أثناء محاولته إنقاذي.
Please save him.
أرجوكم أنقذوه.
Hulu, take care of your sister.
هولو، اعتني بأختك.
Yes, Master.
نعم يا سيدي.
Yingying.
يينغ يينغ.
Calm down.
اهدأ.
I've saved so many people,
لقد أنقذت حياة الكثير من الناس،
so I can definitely save him.
لذا يمكنني بالتأكيد إنقاذه.
No problem.
لا مشكلة.
Gu Tian.
قو تيان.
Please don't die.
أرجوك لا تموت.
We haven't paid you
لم ندفع لك
or found the Treasure of the Sealed Book.
أو عثر على كنز الكتاب المختوم.
We agreed you'd get a share of it, didn't we?
اتفقنا على أن تحصل على حصة منه، أليس كذلك؟
We haven't gone back to Shangyi together.
لم نعد إلى شانغي معًا.
Your brothers are waiting for you.
إخوتك ينتظرونك.
We also said
قلنا أيضاً
we'd be brothers for life,
سنبقى إخوة مدى الحياة،
and we'd keep on living together.
وسنستمر في العيش معًا.
Don't die.
لا تموت.
I can do it.
أستطيع أن أفعل ذلك.
I can save you.
أستطيع إنقاذك.
[The animals in the show are props]
[الحيوانات في العرض هي مجرد دعائم]
[No animals were harmed during the filming]
[لم تتعرض أي حيوانات للأذى أثناء التصوير]
♪Under the sky, light and shadow go together♪
♪تحت السماء، يسير النور والظل جنباً إلى جنب♪
♪The reflection of prosperity and splendor♪
♪انعكاس الرخاء والروعة♪
♪Hides many secrets♪
♪يخفي الكثير من الأسرار♪
♪It's like♪
♪يشبه♪
♪Every page of your life♪
♪كل صفحة من حياتك♪
♪It's all about destiny♪
♪الأمر كله يتعلق بالقدر♪
♪The story has tragedy and comedy♪
♪تحتوي القصة على مأساة وكوميديا♪
♪To discover the mystery♪
♪لاكتشاف اللغز♪
♪We go on adventures♪
♪ننطلق في مغامرات♪
♪We don't run away or compromise easily♪
♪لا نهرب أو نتنازل بسهولة♪
♪When dawn comes♪
♪عندما يأتي الفجر♪
♪The light shines♪
♪يشرق النور♪
♪We follow the path of discovery♪
♪نسلك درب الاكتشاف♪
♪To chase and welcome♪
♪للمطاردة والترحيب♪
♪Every unknown story♪
♪كل قصة مجهولة♪
♪We take a trip together♪
♪نقوم برحلة معًا♪
♪With hot blood and original purpose♪
♪بدم حار وهدف أصلي♪
♪We seize the day and live it to the fullest♪
♪نغتنم اليوم ونعيشه على أكمل وجه♪
♪Leave a mark on our journey♪
♪ اترك بصمة في رحلتنا ♪
♪Scatter the darkness with our hearts♪
♪بدّد الظلام بقلوبنا♪
♪Aspire to make a difference♪
♪اطمح إلى إحداث تغيير♪
♪To discover the mystery♪
♪لاكتشاف اللغز♪
♪We go on adventures♪
♪ننطلق في مغامرات♪
♪We don't run away or compromise easily♪
♪لا نهرب أو نتنازل بسهولة♪
♪When dawn comes♪
♪عندما يأتي الفجر♪
♪The light shines♪
♪يشرق النور♪
♪We follow the path of discovery♪
♪نسلك درب الاكتشاف♪
♪To chase and welcome♪
♪للمطاردة والترحيب♪
♪Every unknown story♪
♪كل قصة مجهولة♪
♪We take a trip together♪
♪نقوم برحلة معًا♪
♪With hot blood and original purpose♪
♪بدم حار وهدف أصلي♪
♪We seize the day and live it to the fullest♪
♪نغتنم اليوم ونعيشه على أكمل وجه♪
♪Leave a mark on our journey♪
♪ اترك بصمة في رحلتنا ♪
♪Scatter the darkness with our hearts♪
♪بدّد الظلام بقلوبنا♪
♪Aspire to make a difference♪
♪اطمح إلى إحداث تغيير♪
♪Make a difference♪
♪أحدث فرقاً♪
♪We take a trip together♪
♪نقوم برحلة معًا♪
♪Through hardships♪
♪رغم المصاعب♪
♪We will find the glory♪
♪سنجد المجد♪
♪Aspire to make a difference♪
♪اطمح إلى إحداث تغيير♪